[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]
So now we've discussed the idea of building a decision stump from data and
إذًا لقد ناقشنا الآن فكرة بناء جذع قرار من البيانات
a little bit of what that data set looks like.
وقليلًا مما تبدو عليه مجموعة البيانات.
Let's discuss now how to pick the right feature to
دعونا نناقش الآن كيفية اختيار الميزة الصحيحة
split on when we're building a decision stump.
للتقسيم عليها عندما نقوم ببناء جذع قرار.
So trying to learn decision stump from data and he was split on credit.
إذًا في محاولة لتعلم جذع القرار من البيانات، سيتم التقسيم على الائتمان.
But the question is what is the best feature to split on and
ولكن السؤال هو ما هي أفضل ميزة للتقسيم عليها
how do we measure that?
وكيف لنا أن نقيسها؟
So in our example we split on credit or we could have split on something else.
لذا في المثال الخاص بنا نقوم بالتقسيم حسب الائتمان أو يمكننا التقسيم حسب شيء آخر.
Let's say we could have split on term of the loan,
دعونا نقول إنه يمكننا التقسيم حسب مدة القرض،
this is a three year loan or a five year loan.
فهناك قرض لأجل ثلاث سنوات وقرض لأجل خمس سنوات،
And the question is, what is better between the two?
والسؤال هو، ما هو الأفضل بين الاثنين؟
What is a better split?
ما هو التقسيم الأفضل؟
And that's what we're going to ask next.
وهذا ما سنسأله بعد ذلك.
And intuitively, a better split is one that gives you lowest
وبشكلٍ بديهي، فإن التقسيم الأفضل هو الذي سيمنحك أدنى
classification error, and that's exactly what we'll explore in the algorithm.
خطأ في التصنيف، وهذا بالضبط هو ما سنستكشفه في الخوارزمية.
We'd like to figure out whether it's better to split on credit or
نحن نود أن نعرف إذا ما كان من الأفضل أن نقوم بالتقسيم حسب الائتمان أم
split on term.
التقسيم حسب الأجل.
And the way we're going to do that is by measuring the number of mistakes
والطريقة التي سنقوم من خلالها بذلك هي عن طريق قياس عدد الأخطاء
each one of the decision stumps makes and
التي يقوم بها كل جذع قرار
pick the one that makes the least number of mistakes, so has lowest error.
واختيار الجذع الذي يعطي أقل عدد من الأخطاء، وبالتالي يكون له معدل الخطأ الأدنى.
And just remember the error is just the number of mistakes
وتذكر فقط أن الخطأ هو مجرد عدد الأخطاء
a classifier makes divided by the total number of data points.
التي يقوم بها التصنيف مقسومًا على العدد الإجمالي لنقاط البيانات.
So, lets start with the root node.
لذا دعونا نبدأ مع عقدة الجذر.
And this is if we made no splits on the decision stump and
وهذا هو إذا لم نقم بأي تقسيمات في جذع القرار
measure the error that we get in that example.
وقمنا بقياس الخطأ الذي نحصل عليه في هذا المثال.
So, as a reminder, we're going to predict y hat to be
لذلك، للتذكير، سنقوم بتنبؤ y hat لتكون
the majority class associated with a particular node.
غالبية الفئة المرتبطة بعقدة معينة.
So, in our case here the class that has most values for
لذا، وفي حالتنا هنا الفئة تحتوي على معظم القيم
the root is going to be the safe class.
وسيكون الجذر هو الفئة الآمنة.
And we're going to compute the classification error of making that
وسنقوم بحساب خطأ التصنيف للقيام بذلك
prediction.
التنبؤ.
So here worse classification error we're just saying that
لذا هنا هو أسوأ خطأ تصنيف نحن فقط نقول إن
all the data points are safe.
كافة نقاط البيانات آمنة.
So we can go ahead and say that there were 22 correct things, 22 were safe and
لذا يمكننا المضي قدمًا وقول إن هناك 22 شيئًا صحيحًا، 22 نحن في مأمن
18 mistakes.
و18 خطأ.
So the classification error here is going to be,
لذا فإن خطأ التصنيف هنا هو،
I'm going to change colors, is going to be 18 / 22 + 18.
سأقوم بتغيير الألوان، سيكون 18 / 22 + 18.
Which is 40.
وهو 40.
So, 18 over 40 which is 0.45.
وهكذا، 18 على 40 وهو 0.45.
It's a binary classification problem.
إنها مسألة تصنيف ثنائي.
You only get 0.45, I mean, you get 0.45 error which is really bad.
وستحصل على 0.45، أعني، ستحصل على خطأ 0.45 وه سيئ حقًا.
And so not splitting on anything gives you a pretty bad result.
لذا فإن عدم التقسيم على أي شيء يمنحك نتيجة سيئة جدًا.
So the question here is, how good is the decision stump that splits on credit?
والسؤال هنا هو، ما مدى جودة جذع القرار الذي يقسم على الائتمان؟
And how does it compare to not splitting on anything,
وكيف يقارن إلى عدم التقسيم على أي شيء،
which had a classification error of 0.45?
والذي كان له خطأ تصنيف بلغ 0.45؟
Is this one better?
هل هذا هو الأفضل؟
So let's look at the decision stump.
لذا دعونا ننظر إلى جذع القرار.
For data points that have excellent credit we're going to predict that they're safe.
بالنسبة لنقاط البيانات التي يكون لها ائتمان ممتاز سنقوم بالتنبؤ بأنها آمنة.
For those that have fair credit,
وبالنسبة لتلك التي لديها ائتمان عادل،
And ones that have poor credit we're going to predict them to be risky.
وتلك التي لديها ائتمان سيء سنقوم بالتنبؤ بأنها ستكون محفوفة بالمخاطر.
And so this is our prediction, and
وبالتالي هذا هو تنبؤنا
this is again the majority value of the data in each one of these nodes.
وهذا هو مرة أخرى قيمة الأغلبية للبيانات في كل واحدة من هذه العقد.
And if you look at how many mistakes we make, you'll see that for
وإذا نظرتم إلى عدد الأخطاء التي قمنا بها، سترى أن
the data that had excellent credit,
البيانات التي كان لها ائتمان ممتاز،
we make zero mistakes because everything was safe there.
قامت بصفر من الأخطاء لأن كل شيء كان آمنًا هناك.
For data that had fair credit, we're going to make four mistakes.
وبالنسبة للبيانات التي كان لها ائتمان عادل، سنقوم بأربعة أخطاء.
There were four risky loans with fair credit.
حيث كان هناك أربعة قروض محفوفة بالمخاطر مع الائتمان العادل.
And then for data that had poor credit, and we'll see there's four mistakes
ثم بالنسبة للبيانات التي كان لها ائتمان سيء، سنرى وجود أربعة أخطاء مرة أخرى
again because there were four safe loans when we had a poor credit.
لأنه كان هناك أربعة قروض آمنة عندما كان لدينا ائتمان سيء.
So let's compute our overall error.
لذلك دعونا نحسب الخطأ الكلي.
We're going to write over here.
سنقوم بالكتابة هنا.
I'm just going to change my colors.
سأقوم فقط بتغيير ألواني.
And we'll see that we make 4 + 4 mistakes.
وسنرى أننا نقوم بـ 4 + 4 من الأخطاء.
So that's 8 out of 40 data points, so that's an error of 0.20, 0.2.
وذلك 8 من أصل 40 نقطة بيانات، لذا فإن هذا هو خطأ يبلغ 0.20، 0.2.
Which is smaller than we had, 0.45.
وهو أصغر مما كان لدينا عند 0.45.
So, we've gone down now from 0.45 to 0.2.
لذا، فقد انخفضنا الآن من 0.45 إلى 0.2.
So splitting on credit seems like a pretty good idea.
وبالتالي فإن التقسيم على الائتمان يبدو فكرة جيدة.
Now let's see what happens when we split on term of the loan.
الآن دعونا نرى ما سيحدث عندما نقوم بالتقسيم على أجل القرض.
We still have term of the loan.
لا يزال لدينا مدة القرض.
If the term is three years, maybe there is 16 safe loans and 4 risky ones.
إذا كانت المدة ثلاث سنوات، ربما هناك 16 قرضًا آمنًا و4 قروض محفوفة بالمخاطر.
So, in this case we're making four mistakes.
لذا، في هذه الحالة نقوم بأربعة أخطاء.
And for five years we predicted risky where there were six safe loans,
وبالنسبة للخمس سنوات التي توقعنا أنها محفوفة بالمخاطر حيث توجد ستة قروض آمنة،
so now we're making six mistakes.
لذا سنقوم الآن بستة أخطاء.
And so if you look at the overall error here it's 4 + 6 / 40.
ولذا إذا نظرنا إلى الخطأ الكلي هنا وهو 4 + 6 / 40.
So that's 10 divided by 40, which is 0.25.
لذا فهذا هو 10 مقسومًا على 40، وهي 0.25.
So overall, if we look at our data,
إذًا عمومًا، إذا ألقينا نظرة على البيانات المتوفرة لدينا،
not splitting on anything, the root node, has 0.45 error,
فإن عدم تقسيم على أي شيء من عقدة الجذر، كان له خطأ 0.45،
splitting on credit has 0.2 error, and splitting on term has 0.25 error.
والتقسيم على الائتمان له خطأ 0.2، والتقسيم على الأجل كان له خطأ 0.25.
So can go back and ask, what is the best choice?
لذا يمكننا أن نعود ونسأل، ما هو الخيار الأفضل؟
Should we split on credit, or should split on term?
هل ينبغي التقسيم على الائتمان، أم ينبغي التقسيم على الأجل؟
The answer now becomes obvious.
والجواب الآن يصبح واضحًا.
Splitting on credit gives you lower classification error, so
فالتقسيم على الائتمان يمنحك أدنى خطأ تصنيف، وبالتالي
this is what our greedy algorithm will do first.
هذا ما ستفعله خوارزمية الجشع لدينا أولًا.
This is the first feature to split on.
هذه هي الميزة الأولى للتقسيم عليها.
And that would be the winner of our selection process.
وستكون هي الفائزة في عملية الاختيار.
So in general, the decision tree splitting
لذا بشكل عام، فإن عملية تقسيم شجرة القرار
process will say given the subset of data at node M,
بإعطاء المجموعة الفرعية البيانات عند العقدة M،
which is what we're looking at, the root node so
وهو ما نبحث عنه في عقدة الجذر حتى الآن
far, we try out every feature xi,
نقوم بتجربة بكل ميزة xi،
which in our case here was credit, term, and income.
وفي حالتنا هنا هي الائتمان، والأجل، والدخل.
And I could see splitting the data according to possible values
ويمكنني أن أرى تقسيم البيانات وفقًا للقيم الممكنة
of each one of these features, and I compute a classification error
لكل واحدة من هذه الميزات، وأن أحسب خطأ التصنيف
of the resulting split, just like we did manually over here.
للتقسيم الناتج، مثلما فعلنا يدويًا هنا.
And then I pick the feature,
ومن ثم اختار الميزة،
which in our case was credit which had the lowest classification error.
وفي حالتنا هذه كانت الائتمان حيث كان له أدنى خطأ تصنيف.
So, if we go back to our decision tree learning algorithm that first challenge
لذا، إذا عدنا إلى خوارزمية تعلم شجرة القرار سنجد أن التحدي الأول
that we had, figuring out what feature to split on, we can now do that using this
الذي كان لدينا، وهو معرفة الميزة التي سنقوم بالتقسيم عليها، يمكننا الآن أن نفعل ذلك باستخدام
feature split selection algorithm that minimizes the classification error.
خوارزمية تحديد ميزة التقسيم التي تقلل من خطأ التصنيف.
So next, we'll explore the other parts of this decision tree learning algorithm.
لذا بعد ذلك، سوف نستكشف أجزاء أخرى من خوارزمية تعلم شجرة القرار هذه.
[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]